Rabo Yusuf

Front End Developer

Front End Developer with three years of experience working with JavaScript, React, Redux, HTML/CSS, Node to deliver exceptional user experiences. Adept at contributing to a highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions, and determining user satisfaction.

Portfolio: https://theraboyusuf.netlify.app/

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/raboyusuf

GitHub: https://github.com/rabobahago

StackOverFlow: https://stackoverflow.com/users/12221293/rabo-yusuf

Email: raboyusuf94@gmail.com

SKILLS:

JavaScript

- CSS/styled component/Bootstrap/SASS
- Git and GitHub
- TypeScript
- React/Redux
- Node
- SQL

EXPERIENCE:

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

The Bulb Africa, Lagos Nigeria

April 2021 – Present

- Refactored codebase from ECMAScript 5 to ES 6, improving user engagement by 10%.
- Designed multiple dynamic and browser compatible pages using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (React, Redux).
- Modified existing software to correct errors, fix bugs and allow adaptation to new hardware to improve performance by more than 30%.
- Designed assessment forms for different customers stages that cut processing times by 30%.

FREELANCE DEVELOPER

Jan 2019 - March 2021

- Worked alongside two peers to build a real-time voice visualization application within three days.
- Gathered and analyzed technical application requirements, increasing overall efficiency by 17%.
- Developed RESTful APIs within a team to serve data based on dynamically chosen user

inputs for a web application with over 100 concurrent users.

• Designed a scalable application architecture, as well as the APIs to support it continuously

EDUCATION:

Masters in Engineering (Energy, CGPA 4.38)

April 2015 – Aug 2018

Bayero University Kano.

Kano State, Nigeria

CERTIFICATION:

Nano Degree in React, Redux and React Native

2021

Udacity United State of America